- **\** +91 8800708940
- ♥ New Delhi, IN

# Javed Khan

Software Developer

# **SUMMARY**

A dedicated coder with **Strengths in Java, Data Structures and Algorithms.** 

Recognized consistently for Exceptional Performance Excellence in multiple National and International projects.

2.5+ years of experience in Java, SpringBoot, MySQL

Total 4.5+ years of experience

working for Multi-National clients at SIEMENS.

Eager to contribute as a software developer.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Java, Java8
- Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA(Micro-Services)
- MySQL

### AWARDS/RECOGNITION

- Special Star Award: For Exceptional work in critical National and International Projects
- Global Talent Search Exam: All India Rank-2 (Silver Medalist)
- National Mathematics Olympiad
   Competition(NMOC): Gold Medalist

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Languages: Hindi (Native), English (Professional), Urdu
- Interests: Playing Chess, Listening to Music

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Solution Engineer/ Software Developer

2017 - Present

### **Siemens Limited**

Gurugram, IN

2013 - 2017

- Worked extensively as Backend Java Developer with SpringBoot microservices and MySQL database (2.5+ years)
- Designed RESTful Web Services and Applications
- Collaborated with developers worldwide to develop quality applications
- Designed Computer Network to implement Cyber Security for clients in Greece, Germany, Ireland, India, Bangladesh etc. (2 years)
- Trained in AGILE Methodology and Certified by "Six Thinking Hats" for second best in Project Management skills

# **KEY DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS**

**Bachelor of Technology (B Tech)** 

- Online Lab Tester | Tech Stack: Java, SpringBoot, JavaScript, MySQL
  - Developed a web application to manage ordering medical tests for patients, updating test results for tester, updating consultation as per the test report.
  - The Govt Authority can foresee all the test results and make proper policies and designate different color codes to regions for better management of resources and containing the spread of diseases
- Restaurant Finder | Tech Stack: Java, SpringBoot
  - Restaurant Finder Application that lets you see rates for your selected items from any Restaurant of your choice

## **EDUCATION**

# Jamia Millia Islamia Delhi, IN • Secured 9.4 CGPA (First Division with Honours) Senior Secondary School (XII) 2012 - 2013 Army Public School Shankar Vihar Delhi, IN • Secured 93.2% Secondary School (X) 2010 - 2011 Army Public School Shankar Vihar Delhi, IN

Secured 9.8 CGPA